<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examples on ECSE 506: Stochastic Control and Decision Theory</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examples on ECSE 506: Stochastic Control and Decision Theory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Gambling</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/optimal-gambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/optimal-gambling/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR This stylized model of optimal gambling was introduced by Kelly (1956) to highlight a relationship between channel capacity (which had been proposed recently by Shannon), and gambling. Our motivation for studying this model is to use it as an illustrative example to show that sometimes it is possible to identify the optimal strategy and value function of MDPs in closed form.
Imagine a gambler who goes to a casino with an initial fortune of \(x_1\) dollars and places bets over time and must leave after \(T\) bets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inventory Management</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/inventory-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/inventory-management/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR The inventory management example illustrates that a dynamic programming formulation is useful even when a closed form solution does not exist. This model also introduces the idea of post-decision state, which is useful in many contexts.
Imagine a retail store that stockpiles products in its warehouse to meet random demand. Suppose the store procures new stocks at the end of each day (and that there is no lead time and stocks are available next morning).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power-delay trade-off in wireless communication</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/power-delay-tradeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/power-delay-tradeoff/</guid>
      <description>In a cell phone, higher layer applications such as voicecall, email, browsers, etc. generate data packets. These packets are buffered in a queue and the transmission protocol decides how many packets to transmit at each time depending the number of packets in the queue and the quality of the wireless channel.
Let \(X_t \in \integers_{\ge 0}\) denote the number of packets buffered at time \(t\) and \(U_t \in \integers_{\ge 0}\), \(U_t \le X_t\), denote the number of packets transmitted at time \(t\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal choice of the best alternative</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/optimal-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/optimal-choice/</guid>
      <description>A decision maker (DM) wants to select the best alternative from a set of \(T\) alternatives. The DM evaluates the alternatives sequentially. After evaluating alternative \(t\), the DM knows whether alternative \(t\) was the best alternative so far or not. Based on this information, the DM must decide whether to choose alternative \(t\) and stop the search, or to permanently reject alternative \(t\) and evaluate remaining alternatives. The DM may reject the last alternative and not make a choice at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call options</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/call-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/examples/call-options/</guid>
      <description>An investor has a call option to buy one share of a stock at a fixed price \(p\) dollars and has \(T\) days to exercise this option. For simplicity, we assume that the investor makes a decision at the beginning of each day.
The investory may decide not to exercise the option but if he does exercise the option when the stock price is \(x\), he effectively gets \((x-p)\).
Assume that the price of the stoch varies with independent increments, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>