<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>state aggregation on ECSE 506: Stochastic Control and Decision Theory</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/tags/state-aggregation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in state aggregation on ECSE 506: Stochastic Control and Decision Theory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/tags/state-aggregation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Theory: State aggregation or discretization or quantization</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/state-aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/state-aggregation/</guid>
      <description>So far, we have studied exact solutions to the dynamic program. When the state space is large (or possibly continuous), an exact solution is not possible due to computational limitations. So, we need to look at approximate solutions.
The simplest form of approximate solution is state aggregation, in which we partition the state space into equivalence classes and assign one state in each class as a representative element of that class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory: Feature abstraction in MDPs</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/feature-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/feature-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>Consider an MDP with continuous state space \(\ALPHABET X\) and finite action space \(\ALPHABET U\). We denote this MDP by \(M = (\ALPHABET X, \ALPHABET U, c, p)\), where for simplicity we assume that the \(p\) is the density of the transition kernel.
Since the state space is continuous, in general, we cannot compute the value functions exactly. The simplest way to proceed is to discretize the state space \(\ALPHABET X\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory: Model approximation in MDPs</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/model-approximation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/stochastic-control/inf-mdp/model-approximation/</guid>
      <description>There are many instances where we may plan using an approximate model. For example, in many applications with large state spaces, we may construct a simulation model of the system and use it to identify an optimal policy using simulation based methods (such as reinforcement learning). Often, the simulation model is only In such instances, we want to know the error in using the policy obtained from the simulation model in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
